http://www.aipm.com.au/about-us/governance/privacy-policy

SubscribeCreate an AccountJobs BoardContact Us
Search for:
JOIN NOW
LOGIN
Forgotten password?
Forgotten password
Search for:
JOIN NOW
LOGIN
Forgotten password?
Forgotten password
Search for:
ABOUT US
Who Is AIPM?
National Certified Project Manager Register
Chartered Project Professional (ChPP)
Contact Us
Who Is AIPM?
PRIVACY POLICY
AIPM's Privacy Statement sets forth our policy in respect to personal information which you may provide to the AIPM. It explains how AIPM collects, uses, discloses and protects this information on our website.
OUR COMMITMENT
This Statement sets out the Australian Institute of Project Management's (AIPM) privacy policy in respect of personal information which you may provide to the AIPM. We recognise that your privacy is very important to you and we are committed to promoting confidence in the manner in which your personal information is handled by us. The statement that follows explains how AIPM collects, uses, discloses and protects this information on its web site.
SUPPORTING INDUSTRY BEST PRACTICE
The AIPM is committed to supporting the National Privacy Principles (NPPs) set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (as amended). Our aim is to support and ensure that it complies with the NPP which forms the basis of the law introduced to strengthen privacy protection for the public. We believe that in supporting industry best practice this statement will address any potential concerns you may have about how personal information you provide to us is stored, used and accessed.
COLLECTION OF INFORMATION
The AIPM receives and stores transaction information, information you enter on our web site or have provided to us in application, registration or administration processes.
Wherever it is lawful and practicable, the AIPM will endeavour to provide you with the option of not identifying yourself or not providing personal information when entering transactions with us.
However, failure to provide the full and complete information as requested may result in a limited ability on our part to offer or deliver complete services to you.
No personal information is collected when you browse our site generally - we do not keep records which identify those who have accessed our site. In addition, personally identifiable information such as name, birthdate and contact details (email addresses) are only collected at specific check points e.g. on-line applications or the Members Only section of our site. All other information will be requested from you directly. Information collected is kept for as long as it is needed to provide the requested service - when your information is no longer required for these purposes it will be removed. However information provided by members will remain in our membership database, which is kept at the AIPM and not maintained by an external party, even after a member has resigned - this is to create an opportunity for those members to be re-instated in the future, as opposed to having to re-join.
USE AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION
The primary purpose in collecting information from you is to enable us to provide services as efficiently as possible. We will only collect and store information about you that is necessary. The information you provide will not be disclosed to third parties. Although we try to circulate the majority of information by electronic means to our members, we occasionally circulate brochures and other information by mail. In this instance we use the same mail-house which has signed a strict confidentiality agreement with the AIPM. The AIPM does not permit third parties to use information about you for any other purpose than to perform the services that AIPM has instructed them to provide.
The AIPM will not, without your consent, disclose personal information for any purpose (a Secondary purpose) other than for the main purpose (Primary purpose) of fulfilling our business commitments to you, except where:
it is required or authorised by law, or for purposes of law enforcement and matters directly related to law enforcement, or the prevention of unlawful activity;
the Secondary purpose is related to the primary purpose (or directly related when sensitive information is involved) and there is a reasonable expectation that we would use or disclose the information in the circumstances;
the AIPM reasonably believes it is necessary to prevent any serious and imminent threat to any person's life, health or safety or the public's health or safety.
The AIPM will not otherwise disclose your personal information to any other party without your consent.
THIRD PARTY RELATIONSHIPS
To provide you with a more informative on-line experience, the AIPM may utilise on-line resources of suppliers, agents and business partners. Such services comprise of links to third party sites that promote additional services and products e.g. endorsed course providers. In any such relationship, the AIPM takes all reasonable steps to ensure that these parties have, and enforce, an adequate privacy policy. Understandably, the privacy policy of a third party might be different to that of the AIPM and it is advisable that you carefully review any third party's privacy policy before using the site's products or services.
STORAGE AND SECURITY
The AIPM will use all reasonable means to ensure that you only provide personal information in a secure environment and when the information is no longer required, it will be destroyed or permanently rendered anonymous.
Where indicated by a lock (on the browser window), we protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information, you input. In conjunction with our key suppliers and agents, we operate secure data networks protected by an industry standard firewall and password protection system. We also take care to ensure that we have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, unauthorised access, alteration, modification or disclosure of your user data under our control.
The security of any information (including personal information) downloaded and stored on your PC or Server is the responsibility of the individual. The individual is also responsible for the correct configuration of the hardware and software he/she uses to access an AIPM web site, along with the physical security and maintenance of that equipment.
Notwithstanding the fact that we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal data including the use of encryption technology, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose on-line. You can help us keep your personal information secure by ensuring that any password you use on our web site is kept strictly confidential, and by logging off when you have finished using a shared computer.
The AIPM imposes strict rules on its employees who have access either to the databases that store your user information or to the servers that host our services and while we cannot guarantee that any unauthorised access, disclosure, loss, misuse or alteration to your data will not occur, we will take all reasonable steps to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. As stated previously, we have not, and will not, permit our membership database to be stored off-site by an external organisation. Access to our database is therefore limited to employees and Chapter Councils of the AIPM.
You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold the AIPM or its agents or suppliers responsible for any breach of security.
ACCESSING AND UPDATING MEMBERS' RECORDS
The AIPM makes all attempts to ensure that all personal information collected and stored in its database is correct and accurate. You may at any time request access to information we have collected from you and obtain a more in-depth explanation about how the information is used by contact us directly at info@aipm.com.au. We will endeavour to meet or advise you of the outcome of a request within seven business days of receipt of your request.
If at any time you wish to change personal information that is incorrect or wish to have your personal information deleted, members can do so on-line from this web site. You also have the right to request access to your personal information at any time. All our staff will be able to assist you with such a request and this information will be forwarded to you within 5 working days.
COMPLAINTS RESOLUTION
The AIPM is committed to providing consumers with a fair and responsive system for handling and resolving complaints. You have a right to complain and to have your complaint handled efficiently. We believe that in receiving your complaint, we are provided with a valuable opportunity to improve the services we deliver to you and maintain your confidence in AIPM and our services.
If at any time you wish to lodge a complaint in respect of the handling, use or disclosure of your personal information by the AIPM, please send your written complaint to the General Manager of the AIPM, at AIPM National Office: info@aipm.com.au, ph.02 8288 8750, or at Level 23, 100 Miller Street, North Sydney NSW 2060
LIABILITY DISCLAIMER
The AIPM will use all reasonable endeavours to protect and keep confidential any personally identifiable information in its possession in relation to its members, subscribers or website visitors. If any confidential or personally identifiable information is accessed by a third party, whether by negligence or otherwise of the AIPM, its agents, suppliers, contractors, related bodies corporate, affiliates or associated parties, to the extent permitted by law, the AIPM is not liable for any loss, damage, costs, liability or other form of contribution.
Further information on Privacy Further information may be obtained on privacy issues in Australia by visiting the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner's web site at www.privacy.gov.au
ABOUT US
MEMBERSHIP
CERTIFICATION
EVENTS
AWARDS
COURSES
NEWS
RESOURCES
Chartered Project Professional (ChPP)
COVID-19
MY AIPM
Home
Who Is AIPM?
Who Is AIPM?
Copyright 2020 Australian Institute of Project Management
